**Charlie Smith** 

Battersea, London

Phone: (+44) 74 2838 3229

Email: charlie@blacksmithcomputing.co.uk

Skype: robert.charles.smith

# **Objective**

To deliver value to my clients through quickly adapting to the client's expected practices, and then going beyond by delivering maintainable and automatically tested software that leverages both my increasing experience and industry best practices.

## **Relevant Work Experience**

Note: From May 2017 – Sep 2017, I was travelling between New Zealand and the UK and working on my own OSS project, chromewhip.

### Kordia, Wellington, NZ - 6 month contract

October 2016 - May 2017

- Technologies: Python 3, Ember.js, Django, PostgresSQL, Oracle, numpy, pandas, Ansible, Jenkins, Openstack, Linux
- Successfully delivered on a team of 3, the new customer facing portal for providing real-time network data and insights for their internet and cyber securities products, targeted at enterprise IT users. Involved porting of some code and data from a legacy platform running pyramid, Oracle 10g and in-house SOAP services and integrating with existing Microsoft services such as Active Directory.

# Map Of Agriculture, Christchurch, NZ - 6 month contract

May 2016 – October 2016

- Technologies: Python 3, Go, Django, celery, PostgresSQL, numpy, pandas, PowerBI, AWS, Linux
- With original developers leaving within 1 month of starting, took full responsibility of an in-house data wrangling and financial dashboard platform for corporate farmers. Enhanced and simplified maintenance of the system by moving functionality from celery jobs to go subroutines (apex) running on AWS Lambda

#### Pensolve, Christchurch, NZ - Technical Co-Founder

Aug 2015 - May 2016

- Technologies: Python 3, Ember.js, Flask, celery, PostgresSQL, Docker, Azure, Linux
- Architected and developed a SaaS platform that helps enhance the peer review process of engineering calculation in Microsoft Excel spreadsheets. Our key feature is a complex algorithm that can recognise layout and semantics of spreadsheet calculations and transform into a handwritten format engineers can easily understand.
- Deeply involved in all other business administration and tasks such as sales and marketing.

## Kordia, Wellington, NZ - Support Systems Software Developer

Nov 2014 - Aug 2015

- Technologies: Python 2, PostgresSQL, Oracle, Ansible, Linux
- Provide 24/7 on-call support on a roster basis to the operations team on all of the above systems, successfully dealing with urgent issues on mission-critical systems under pressure.
- Improved development cycle efficiency from day one, modernizing the workflow with *Ansible* and *Jenkins*. Within 2 months, development cycle time for one of the pilot projects had shrunk by more than half, by introducting full pipeline continuous integration and deployment system.

Note: From Feb 2014 – Aug 2014, I was on a Latin America travelling OE.

LinkedIn: <a href="https://nz.linkedin.com/in/chuckus">https://nz.linkedin.com/in/chuckus</a>
Github: <a href="https://github.com/chuckus">https://github.com/chuckus</a>

- Technologies: Embedded C++, Python 2, Objective-C, Linux
- An early promotion to intermediate level, attributed to sustained effort and tangible successes in my areas
  of responsibility.
- Supported development and maintenance of Taits low latency, high transaction simulators, simulating Tait products within a networked environment written in Python mainly using *tornado* for stress testing.
- Contributed to the development using C++ on OSI Layer 2 and 3 of the P25 Phase 2 communications standard, targeting the TI DaVinci platform within the Tait TB9400 series base station.
- Successfully developed a working prototype for a situational awareness application sent to the US during the APCO 2013 convention in the US to prototype a disaster response solution with international partners.
- Mentored two summer students to provide support for the above projects.

#### Tait Communications, Christchurch, NZ - Junior Test Analyst

Nov 2011 - Oct 2012

- Technologies: Python 2, numpy, scipy, matplotlib, Linux
- Responsible for the maintenance, enhancement and support of the automated RF performance and regression test framework written in Python for the TBC base station series, which I had only 2 weeks to absorb the working knowledge from the sole author and maintainer who then left the company.
- Received an internal annual award for excellence in junior engineering, for "consistently performing an outstanding job since inheriting a complex testing tool chain."

### Tait Communications, Christchurch, NZ - Junior Design Engineer

Nov 2010 - Nov 2011

- Technologies: Python 2, C++, gnuradio, Linux
- Summer and part time job designing and implementing analogue and digital radio signaling enhancements into SDRTS. This allowed the company to reduce reliance on expensive analog test equipment, and replace some of the testing with this cheaper, open-source tool.

#### Education

Scalable Machine Learning with certificate, Online edX course run by BerkeleyX Functional Programming Principles in Scala

August 2015 Nov 2013

Online Coursera course run by École Polytechnique Fedérale De Lausanne

Startup Engineering, Online Coursera course run by Stanford University

Sep 2013

Bachelor of Engineering with Honours in Electrical and Electronic Engineering (2nd class, 1st division) University of Canterbury, Christchurch, New Zealand

Feb 2008 - Nov 2011

## **Extra Curricular Activities**

- **Calisthenics** Starting 3 months ago after wanting a change from weight lifting.
- **Ukulele** Started as an alternative to Guitar so that I could take an ukulele while traveling.
- **Spanish** Spent 5 weeks learning Spanish in Nicaragua and Guatemala and regularly maintain my knowledge.

## Referees

Referees can be provided upon request